杰森∶迈克!迈克!
Jason: Mike!Mike!Mike!
迈克!如果你在这里,如果你现在就出来的话,
If you're in there, things'll go easier on you, if you come out now!
我就饶过你!我愚蠢的以为,从高中毕业后,
But not much!You know,
你不会再去找校长的麻烦,想不到两年后,
I stupidly assumed that it would be impossible for you to get in trouble,
你还是老样子!但是,
with your high school principle two years after you graduate!But, oh no!
不!无论如何你要想办法解决.我知道你在里面,
Somehow you managed to pull it off.I know you're in her Mike.
迈克.迈克,我现在数到三,
Mike, I'm gonna count to three, and if you're not out I'm gonna...
如果你还不出来的话,我就撕烂你的充水床垫!
slit your water bed Mike!
玛莲∶你好,我要找……哦!哦!
Mylene: Hi, I'm looking for...Oh oh.
杰森∶我也在找他.如果我找到他的话,
Jason: I'm looking for him too.
你也就不会想留下来了.
And if I find him, you're not gonna want what's left.
玛莲∶你是他的爸爸?
Mylene: You're his father?
杰森∶哦!是的.
Jason: Oh yes.
玛莲∶哇!他说的是真的耶,你真的很难对付!
Mylene: Wow!He wasn't kidding, you are nuts!
杰森∶哼!?哦.哈哈,
Jason: Huh?Oh.Ha ha, no.I was just gonna...
不.我只是,我只是要把他的充水床垫切开.
I was gonna slice his water bed.No I wasn't really...I was...err...
我并不是真的要……我……听我说,如果我是你的话,我才不会等在这里去见迈克呢……
Look, I wouldn't stick around to see Mike, if I was you.
玛莲∶迈克是谁?
Mylene: Who's Mike?
杰森∶你要找的家伙呀.
Jason: The guy you came to see.
玛莲∶哦!不.我是来找本的,我们有约会.
Mylene: Oh, no.I'm here to see Ben, we have a date.
杰森∶本?你几岁了?
Jason: Ben?How old are you?
玛莲∶十八岁.
Mylene: Eighteen.
杰森∶ 18!!真好,
Jason: Eighteen!!Great, I got one kid who won't grow up and another who
我看我的儿子们现在是一个总是长不大,一个,却又长的太快了!
is growing up too fast!
本∶既然你要找迈克,
Ben: Since you're looking for Mike,
那我和玛连就不妨碍你了.
me and Marlene will just get the heck out of your way.
玛莲∶酷.
Mylene: Cool.
杰森∶等等!等我处理好迈克后,我马上就要找你了.他在哪里?
Jason: Now, wait a second!I'm gonna get to you, right after I deal with
Mike.Now where is he
本∶我也不知道.快点,我们走.
Ben: I have no idea.Come on, let's go.
杰森∶嗨!
Jason: Hey, you're not going out with an eighteen year old girl;
你不能和18岁的女孩约会;你才……反正就是不行!
you're only th...You're just not!
玛莲∶你才几岁?
Mylene: You're only what?
本:十三.
Ben: Thirteen.
玛莲∶啊啊 !!
Mylene: Arrrgghh!!
迈克∶嗨!爸爸,是你在大声的叫我吗?我刚才没有听见.
Mike: Hey Dad, were you yelling for me?I couldn't hear you.
杰森∶迈克,我警告你!
Jason: Mike, let me warn you!I'm ready to kill you!
我恨不得杀了你!说话小心点.
Now choose your next words very carefully.
迈克∶等等!从这里开始.
Mike: Hang on!There, go ahead.
杰森∶好了,现在最好有个人来做个解释!
Jason: OK, somebody better explain something to me now!
我给你们两个选择:你们可以给我编一些无稽之谈……不过我总是会知道真相的,
Fine, there's two ways we can on this;
到时,
you can either make up some cock and bull story...
迈克,我可不会轻易放过你.
I'll get the truth eventually Mike, and you'll be severely punished!
本∶还有呢?
Ben: Or?
杰森∶或者是你们主动告诉我发生的一切,
Jason: Or, you can tell me the exact truth, as it happened,
不过我还是不会放过你们!!
and I'll punish you severely!!
迈克∶爸爸,那说和不说事实有什么区别呀...
Mike: Dad, I'm not seeing the upside of going with the truth here...
我回想了一下,所有的事情都是如此的清晰!
and yet when I think about it for a moment, it all seems so damn clear!
就是,上个星期,我正在楼上房间里像平常一样学习,
Ah, Ok, last week, I was up in my room, studying as usual,
我学的太认真了,都不确定当时的时间了....
and I'm not sure exactly what time it was because I was so into it...
杰森∶事实!
Jason: The truth!
迈克∶恩,我正在睡觉……
Mike: OK, I was sleeping...
(开始回想)
(We go back in time)
迈克∶……然后我听到车道上有一只刺猬在叫.
Mike: ...and I heard the little hedgehog out on the driveway.
路易斯∶伙计!
Louis: Dude!
本∶路易斯,别那么大声!
Ben: Louis, keep it down!
路易斯:你找到那个了么,本?
Louis: You got the stuff, Ben?
本∶是,但是路易斯,我不知道这是不是你要的那个.
Ben: Yeah, but, Louis, I don't know if this is right.
路易斯∶伙计!我带现金来了,帮个忙,把资料给我!
Louis: Dude, I got the cash, come on and help me!
本∶好吧,给你.
Ben: Well, OK.
路易斯∶伙计!
Louis: Dude!
本∶爸爸,事情根本不是这样的..
Ben: That's not the way it was at all, Dad
路易斯∶本杰明.
Louis: Benjamin.
本∶路易斯,见到你真是太惊奇了.
Ben: Louis, what a pleasant surprise.
路易斯∶我讨厌欺骗,
Louis: I hate to impose,
但我听说在麦维尔·杜威高中的人,谁要是有了理论上的困难,
but I heard that when one is having academic difficulties at Dewey High
都可以来找你.
School, you're the man to see.
本:当然.每当厌倦了那些废话的时候……我总是会厌倦,
Ben: Certainly.Just as soon as I've finished taking out the trash...
即使没有人问我.
which I always do, even when I haven't been asked.
路易斯∶好家伙.
Louis: What a guy.
(回到现在)
(present time)
迈克∶好了,爸爸,你现在要相信谁,我还是倒垃圾的人?
Mike: OK, Dad, who are you gonna believe; me or the trash man?
本∶嗨!伙计.
Ben: Hey dude.
杰森∶继续,迈克.
Jason: Go ahead, Mike.
迈克∶好.
Mike: OK.
(继续回忆)
(back to the story)
路易斯∶帮帮忙啦,伙计!
Louis: So come on and help me, man!
本∶好吧,给你.
Ben: Errm...OK.
路易斯∶伙计!
Louis: Dude!
迈克∶本到底在做什么呀?
Mike: What the heck was Ben doing?
路易斯又在学校里做什么呢?本,
And what the heck was Louis doing still in high school?
发生什么事了?
Ben, what the heck is going on around here?
本∶现在不是告诉你的时候.开萝尔,接电话!!
Ben: Not now.Carol, Phone for you!!
开萝尔∶我马上下来.
Carol: I'll be right down.
迈克∶本,你最好现在就告诉我发生了什么事情……
Mike: Ben, either you tell me what's going on right now...
本∶好的!迈克,快,到前楼梯那里.轻点!
Ben: Alright!Now, Mike, the front stairs.But be quiet!
迈克∶本,到底怎么了……
Mike: Ben, what the heck is...
本∶嘘.
Ben: Shh.
开萝尔∶好吧,一个字也不说...就坐在那里,连声音也不出,毛病!如果这个人再来电话,就说我不在.
Carol: Fine, don't say a word...Just sit there, not making a sound, pervert!If that jerk calls for me again, tell him I'm not home
迈克∶好了,本,
Mike: OK Ben, I got it.
我知道了.你把开萝尔的学期论文装进裤子里干什么...快告诉我.
Now, you've got Carol's term papers stuffed in your pants...Now talk to me.
本∶好吧.
Ben: Well...
麦琪∶嗨,伙计们好!
Maggie: Well, "dude" to you too young man.
路易斯∶伙计?伙计!!
Louis: Dude?Dude!!
(回到现在)
(present time)
杰森∶迈克没有帮你卖开萝尔的学期论文?
Jason: You sold Carol's term papers with no help from Mike whatsoever!
迈克∶对不起,爸爸.你就先拷问一下他,我去嘘嘘.
Mike: Excuse me Dad.While you ream the lad, I'm going to floss.
本:爸爸,我没有准备卖.其实斯提克的哥哥,
Ben: Well Dad, I didn't plan to sell 'em.
范可,你在英语上需要帮助,而且他说仅此一次,
See, Stinky's brother, Funky, he needed help in English...
他会保密.所以,我给了他一份.一份!
and he said it would only be this one time...and that he'd keep it quiet.
一份!我怎么知道,范可这么不守信用.
So, I gave him one.One!One!How did I know, Funky had a big mouth?
杰森∶他的名字叫范可?
Jason: His name is Funky?
本:没错.而给路易斯的那篇,
Ben: Yeah and the...
是我卖出去的第一本...
and the one to Louis, well that was the first one I ever sold...
如果不是迈克的话,我早就不干了.
and it would have stopped there if it wasn't for Mike.
杰森∶迈克!
Jason: Mike!
迈克∶我在嘘嘘.不能说话.
Mike: I'm flossing.I can't talk.
本∶我可以说.
Ben: Well, I can.
是他跟我说如果我不做的话,就是白白的错失良机,
Somebody said, I was missing a golden opportunity;
我应该抓住这次机会.
somebody said I should ride this comet.
迈克∶爸爸,你会相信谁呢?我还是他?
Mike: Dad, again, who are you gonna believe?Me or Carl Sagin, here.
杰森∶继续,卡尔.
Jason: Go ahead, Carl.
(本继续回忆他的事情)
(Ben's story, back in time)
本∶本起初还怀疑开萝尔的论文在麦维尔·杜威高中是否有市场,但是,
Ben: Well, Mike suspected the real market for Carol's papers was at Dewey
事实是,它们非常抢手……
High.Well, they did so well the first time...
学生∶(强烈要求要论文)
Pupils: (screaming for papers)
本∶好,大家不必担心,
Ben: OK, don't worry everybody, I'll be back lunch time tomorrow.
明天午餐时间我会再来的.记住,这些只是做学习的参考.
And remember these are to be used only as study guides.
玛莲∶你是新来的吧?
Mylene: You're new here, aren't you?
本∶没错,这是我来这里的第一天.
Ben: Well...it is my first day here.
玛莲∶恩,我早就猜到了.我认识麦维尔·杜威所有性感的家伙.
Mylene: That's what I figured.I know all the cute guys at Dewey.
本∶性感的家伙!!实话跟你说,我……
Ben: Cute guys!!To tell you the truth I'm...
玛莲∶我是玛莲,住在 8516温斯顿大街,父母都要上班.
Mylene: Mylene, eight five one six Winston Avenue, both my parents work.
本∶本.他们是做什么的?
Ben: Ben.What kind of work do they do?
玛莲∶你知道么,我经常被危险的家伙所吸引.
Mylene: You know, I've always been attracted by dangerous guys.
本:危险的家伙?
Ben: Dangerous guys?
玛莲∶呵呵,
Mylene: Well yeah, someone selling term papers right here in the hallway...
你居然敢公然在大厅售卖学期论文……真是酷必了.
you were so cool.
本∶我想,他们会把我怎么样?开除我吗?
Ben: I figure, what are they gonna do?kick me out of this school?
玛莲∶那你今晚有空吗?
Mylene: So, are you free tonight?
本∶啊,今晚有空,怎么了?
Ben: Ah, free, tonight, why?
玛莲∶恩,我想我们可以约会.
Mylene: Well, I figured we could go out.
我在汽车电影院看过一部不错的电影.
There's this great movie I've already seen at the drive in.
本∶如果你已经看了……哦!
Ben: If you've already seen it...Oh.
玛莲∶那你什么时候来接我?
Mylene: So, what time are you gonna pick me up?
本:哦,来接你?我不能来接你,我没有驾照.
Ben: Err...pick you up?I can't pick you up, I don't have licence right now.
玛莲∶为什么?
Mylene: Why?
本∶……被吊销了……因为在街道上赛车.被抓啦.
Ben: Err...suspended...street racing.Stuff happens.
玛莲∶哦,你真坏.没关系,我有车.我来接你.地址是?
Mylene: Oh, you're so bad.Well, I have a car.I'll pick you up at your place.What's your address?
本∶不过如果你去我家接我的话,可能会有点小问题……
Ben: Well there could be a little bit of a problem there...
校长∶打扰你们实在抱歉……
Principle: I just want to apologise to you two young people...
玛莲∶杜威尔先生,我们只是……
Mylene: Mr.Dewitt, we were just...
校长:不不不不不,玛莲.
Principle: No no no no no Mylene.As the principle, it's my fault.
作为校长,这是我的责任.
The engraved invitations to class were late out the printer.
请帖印晚了.所以我们要用铃声来通知会议开始.
So we've been relying on an annoying bell to let folks know when our sessions
米克帕!米克帕!
begin.Mikopa!Mikopa!
玛莲∶杜威尔先生,对不起……
Mylene: I'm sorry Mr.Dewitt...
本∶嗨!他已经说了是他的过失了!
Ben: Hey, he said it was his fault!
校长∶你叫什么满足,小鬼头?
Principle: What's your name you little insect?
本∶本.
Ben: Ben...
校长∶本什么?
Principle: Ben what?
本∶本……
Ben: Ben...
玛莲∶本是新来的,先生.
Mylene: Ben's new here sir.
校长:哦!不知者无罪!
Principle: Oh, well then, that changes everything doesn't it.
不过呢,你最好还是马上让你们的屁股回到教室,
In that case, get your little buns into that class room right now,
否则,我们把它们吊在学校的旗杆上?好了,
or I'm gonna have 'em flying from the school flagpole, capisce?
快回去.不要遇见温柔的副校长先生.
Alright Leonard, freeze!And drop that vice principle...gently Mister.
玛莲∶嗨!你的地址呢?
Mylene: Hey, what's your address?
本∶罗宾汉15巷,怎么了?
Ben: Fifteen Robin Hood lane, why?
玛莲∶当然是我要来接你啦.7点见.
Mylene: How else am I gonna pick you up?See you at seven.
本∶等等!
Ben: Wait!
玛莲∶不行,我要去上卫生课了.
Mylene: I can't, I gotta get to class...Health.
本:我住在车库上面的房间里.不管怎么样,
Ben: I live above the garage, so whatever you do,
你都不能从前门进!我爸爸很神经质的!
don't come to the front door!My dad's a total lunatic!
校长∶小伙子,原谅我刚刚说的不够清楚.快回到你的教室,否则就等着好看!!!
Principle: Son.Forgive me for not being clear, earlier.Get in to class or die!!!
(回到现在)
(Back to present)
杰森∶哦!本,本,你难道不知道事情已经失去控制了吗?你不知道你越陷越深了吗?
Jason: Oh Ben, Ben, didn't you know things were getting out of hand?Didn't you know you were getting in deeper?
本∶我知道.如果我不听迈克的话,
Ben: I sure did.
我肯定就这样结束了.爸爸,
And it would have ended right there, if it hadn't been for Mike.
不管我做什么,都是受了迈克的坏影响.
Look Dad, whatever I did, Mike was my bad influence.
迈克∶本,怎么回事?难道我有让你去和18岁的女孩子约会吗?
Mike: What's wrong Ben?Did I ever tell you to go out with an eighteen year old woman?
本∶你有!
Ben: Yes!
(继续回忆)
(Back to the story in the past)
本∶抓住机会!!谢谢你,迈克!
Ben: Ride the comet!!Thanks a lot, Mike!
迈克∶怎么了,你被抓住了?
Mike: Well, what happened, did you get caught?
本∶不是.因为你现在有个18岁的女孩子强迫我陪她去汽车电影院,
Ben: No.Because of you an eighteen year old woman is forcing me to go
在她的车里,谁知道要做什么事情?
to the drive in with her, in her car, to do God-knows what!
迈克∶这不好吗?
Mike: And this is bad?
本∶你开什么玩笑?她的爸妈都去上班了,她是学卫生的.
Ben: Are you kidding?Both of her parents work, and she takes Health.
迈克∶本,你是怎么想的,伙计?拜托,
Mike: Benny, excuse me!What are you thinking, man?
把握机会,本,这就是我们生存的意义所在!
Come on, get a hold of yourself!Benny, this is what we all live for!
本∶对我来说,是件坏事情.我必须到城外去!286美元,可以到多远?
Ben: It's bad for me.I gotta get out of town!How far would two hundred and eighty six Dollars get me?
迈克∶可以到这里!嗨!你都有差不多300美元了,然后还有一个18岁的女孩子要来接你……本,我都没有过这样的经历!
Mike: All the way to here!Hey, you have got almost three hundred Dollars, and an eighteen year old girl who is coming over here to pick you up....Benny, I don't even have that!
本:我今天也有一个十二年级历史的报告要做.
Ben: And I also have an oral report due tomorrow in twelfth grade history.
迈克∶管它呢.
Mike: Forget about the history.
本∶但是,我临时小考考的很好的.
Ben: But, I did so well on the pop quiz.Mike, I'm thirteen.
迈克,我才13岁.你第一次和18岁的女孩子约会的是在几岁的时候?
How old were you when you went out with your first eighteen year old?
迈克∶恩,差不多16岁.是不是约你的那个女孩子很丑呀?
Mike: Well, I was only...errm...sixteen.Alright, but we're talking about a real ugly girl here, right?
Ben: Na!She's cute.She looks just like that girl from Mr.Belvedere
迈克∶你肯定她长的不像Belvedere先生?
Mike: You sure she doesn't look like Mr.Belvedere?
本∶才不呢,我跟你说,
Ben: No, I'm telling you,
她有着修长的双腿和丰满的褪部...
she has got legs that connect and lumps and everything man!
迈克∶本,
Mike: Benny..err...then what in the heck is she doing with a thirteen
那她为什么要找一个像你这样才13岁的瘪三呢?
year old horn bowl, like you?
本∶迈克,我快要崩溃了!当她知道我没有18岁,不酷也不危险的时候,当爸妈知道我把开萝尔的学期论文拿出去卖了的时候,当杜威尔先生知道我根本就不在麦维尔·杜威中学上学的时候!啊,我死定了!!
Ben: Mike, it's all gonna fall apart!She's gonna find out I'm not eighteen and cool and dangerous!And Mom and Dad are gonna find out I've been selling Carol's term papers!Mr.Dewitt will find out I don't go to Dewey High!And I'm dead!!
迈克:算了,本!本,不要管这些了.你不要管蒂维特,你都不用去学校!我是说他是你的一种经历.
Mike: Come on, Ben!Ben, let's just deal with these things, one at a time, OK?You don't have to worry about Dewitt, I mean, you don't even go to that school!I mean what's he got an extradition treaty with your Junior high?
本∶不错,但是……
Ben: Yeah but...
迈克∶至于你卖开萝尔的论文的事,爸妈知道了肯定不会有你好过,
Mike: And as for Mom and Dad finding out about you selling Carol's papers...
不出这个星期,你就死定了.
Well you're probably right, you'll be dead within the week.
但是,我还是要告诉你,
But, I'm telling you, you're going on a date with an eighteen year old Bennie!
你马上要和一个18岁的女孩子约会了,那就先享乐后再说!
It'll take hours to wipe that smile off your face!
本∶你是这样想的?
Ben: You think so?
迈克∶哦!本,我认为是.相信我,
Mike: Oh Benny, I know so.Take it form me, go on the date!Watch!Look!
去约会!去观察!去看!去听!长大!
Listen!Grow!
本∶迈克不但怂恿我去约会,
Ben: Not only did Mike talk me into the date,
还给我想出了一个逃出房子的计划.
he even came up with a plan to get me out of the house.
麦琪∶本,你怎么没吃.
Maggie: Ben, you're not eating.
开萝尔∶快点,有人打911了!
Carol: Quick, somebody call 911!
迈克∶大家是否介意我在下面看电视?我刚刚在我的房间里设置了害虫炸弹.
Mike: Hey guys, do you mind if I watch TV down here, I just set of a bug bomb in my apartment?
开萝尔∶那你为什么不直接叫你的朋友走呢?
Carol: Well, why didn't you just ask your friends to leave?
我今晚热死了!
Boy, I'm hot tonight!
迈克∶呵呵,开萝尔,这样才对嘛!
Mike: Yeah, that was a good one Carol!
开萝尔∶你说什么?
Carol: Pardon me?
迈克∶你刚才说的是个不错的玩笑.很高兴见到你有那么一点点的幽默感了.
Mike: It was a good joke.I mean it's good to see you starting to develop a sense of humour.
开萝尔∶哦!谢谢.
Carol: Well, gee, thanks.
迈克∶正好可以说明你的衣着.
Mike: Which explains that outfit you're wearing.
迈克∶大家都别动!我去接!本,找你的!
Mike: Nobody move!I got it!Ben, telephone for you!
本∶你好,你好.没人说话呀.
Ben: Hello.Hello.There's nobody on the phone.
迈克∶哦,你如果叫臭虫,可能就会有人说了.
Mike: Well, maybe if you tell stinky to speak up, Ben.
本∶哦!对,臭虫,说话.
Ben: Oh yeah.Stinky, speak up.I can hear him now.Let me ask.
我现在听见他说话了.让我问问.臭虫问我今天晚上是否可以去他家过夜?
Stinky wants to know if it's OK if I stay over at his house tonight.
杰森∶本,你今天晚上不是有家庭作业吗?
Jason: Ben, you have homework tonight, don't you?
本∶是的,但是我的临时小考考的很好哦.
Ben: Yeah, but I did so well in my pop quiz today.
麦琪∶亲爱的,你就让他去吧.
Maggie: Honey, he does beat the heck out of Stinky sleeping over here.
杰森∶好吧.本,玩得开心点.
Jason: Oh, yeah, enjoy it Ben.
本∶知道了.
Ben: Right.
麦琪∶宝贝,你还没有回答他去不去呢.
Maggie: Honey, you didn't tell him, yes or no.
本:他知道我要来.我要去拿东西.他们买的.
Ben: He knows I'll be there.I'm gonna go get my stuff.They bought it.
迈克∶太好了.
Mike: Great.
本∶还有一个问题--如果玛莲今晚不邀请我去她家过夜,那该怎么办呢?
Ben: Just one question- what if Mylene does invite me to sleep over at her house tonight?
迈克∶本,你可不能到玛莲家去过夜,知道了吗?等你们从汽车电影院回来后,你就直接来我的房间!
Mike: Benny, you're not sleeping over at Mylene's house, OK?I mean, after you get back from the drive in, you're gonna go stay up at my place!
本∶但你不是设置了害虫炸弹么?哦,愚蠢的问题.
Ben: But didn't you just set off a bug bomb up there?OK, stupid question.
迈克∶一切安排妥当.你上去我的房间,等你的女人吧,我要走了,我知道爸爸把古龙香水藏在哪里.
Mike: OK, now look.You go up in my room, wait for your woman, and I'm gonna go, and I know where Dad keeps the good  cologne.
本∶好了,迈克,如果我今天晚上没有花掉这286美元的话,剩下的都是你的.
Ben: Alright, Mike, whatever I don't spend of the two hundred and eighty six Dollars tonight, is yours.
迈克∶谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
开萝尔∶你知道收视指南在哪里吗?
Carol: Do you know where the TV guide is?
迈克∶知道.
Mike: Yeah.
开萝尔∶那你要告诉我吗?
Carol: Well are you gonna tell me?
迈克∶不会.
Mike: No.
(门铃)
(door bell)
校长∶开萝尔西维尔,你过的好吗?
Principle: Carol Seaver, how the heck are you?
开萝尔∶杜威尔先生;真令人惊讶,快进屋来.
Carol: Mr.Dewitt, what a surprise, please come in.
校长∶非常抱歉没有提前打电话就过来了,
Principle: Forgive me for not calling,
因为这件有点敏感,
but this is something of a delicate matter,
我又不想惊动大家,
and I didn't want to upset any one,
我现在有点六神无主了.
in case I am completely out of my mind.
开萝尔∶没关系,我爸爸是心理学家.
Carol: Well, my dad's a psychiatrist.
校长∶恩,不管怎样,我是个不错的管家,对吗?
Principle: Well, then either way, I'm in good hands, right?
麦琪∶我知道,我知道,
Maggie: I know, I know,
但是他上次借宿别人家的时候,我都没有闻到床单上有什么味道呀!
but I never got the smell out of the sheets from the last time he slept
杜威尔先生,你有什么事吗?
over!Mr.Dewitt, what are you doing here?
校长∶哦!由于社区选举人的指挥,我们要加班,
Principle: Oh, working after hours, without any over time,
还没有任何的加班工资,但是,为什么要说这些呢?
thanks to the wisdom of the voters of our community, but, why get into that?
杰森:等等!我的孩子已经不在你那里了.
Jason: Hey, wait a minute!We don't have any kids in your school any more.
校长∶但是,他们的作品还在.
Principle: But, their legacy lives on.Ever heard this before?"
听过这个吗?"
Finally we have a society which I, a woman, can be feminine yet forceful;
最后我们的社会会接受女强人,
free to run a corporation and still experience the wonder and beauty of
女人也可以自由的开公司,生小孩."
giving birth."
开萝尔∶当然听过,这是我告别演讲中的一段.
Carol: Well sure, that was part of my Valedictory address.
校长∶啊哈!
Principle: Aha.I knew Jimmy Droppo wasn't about to experience the wonder
我就知道吉米Droppo才不会要经历生产的奇妙和美丽!
and beauty of didley!
杰森∶吉米droppo与这有什么关系?
Jason: What's Jimmy Droppo got to do with this?
校长∶他今天把这个做为自己的演讲来讲了.
Principle: He delivered this speech today, as his own.
开萝尔∶真的?怎么会到他手上的?
Carol: Really?How'd it go over?
麦琪∶杜威尔先生,
Maggie: Mr.Dewitt, are you suggesting that Carol has something to do with
你的意思是说这件事情是开萝尔做的?
this?
校长∶哦!我可没那样说……
Principle: Oh, I'm not suggesting anything of the kind...
杰森∶那你是什么意思呢……
Jason: Well what exactly are you...
校长∶再听听这个吧.路易斯Dibble的高级历史,"法国革命和暴政统治."
Principle: Well just listen.From Louis Dibble for Senior History, "The French Revolution and Exercise in Rudeness."
开萝尔∶那是我写的!
Carol: I wrote that!
校长∶对.还有,
Principle: Precisely.Or, from Joey Biden, for Health, "Cosmetic History,
Joey Biden的卫生论文,"美容历史,浅谈鼻子."
Just Say Nose."
开萝尔∶那也是我写的!
Carol: That's mine too!
校长∶我还有其他53份例证.
Principle: And I have fifty three other examples.
麦琪∶杜威饵先生,开萝尔为什么要……
Maggie: Mr.Dewitt, why would Carol...
校长:我也非常厌恶.
Principle: I am just as sick about it as you are.
不管怎么说,
After all, Carol was Dewey High's most hallowed hooter.
开萝尔是非常出色的.但是,
Yet, I hold the documentary evidence in my hand that someone has prostituted
我认为有人在卖她的论文.
her work.
杰森∶杜威尔先生,我很了解我的女儿,
Jason: Mr.Dewitt, I know my daughter,
我知道这件事情一定与她无关!
and I know she hasn't had anything to do with this!
校长∶哦!我没说是开萝尔,我说,是某人.
Principle: Oh, I didn't say Carol, I said, someone.
本∶好了,我可不想让她觉得我很吝啬……表演时间到了.
Ben: Na, I don't want her to think I'm cheap...on the other hand.It's show time.
迈克∶嗨!本,你不能出去了!
Mike: Hey Benny, you gotta get out of here!
本∶你发疯了啊?我正在把握机会!
Ben: Are you crazy?I'm riding this comet!
迈克∶不,不,不.
Mike: No no no, forget about the comet, alright?
别想什么机会了.现在,
Now, Dewitt and Mom and Dad are downstairs.
杜威尔,妈妈和爸爸都在楼下呢.他们迟早会知道事情的真相的.
Now it's only a matter of time before they figure this whole thing out.
本∶你不是跟我说什么都不用担心的吗?
Ben: But you said I had nothing to worry about!
迈克∶听着,本!
Mike: Listen Benny!You should not have sold Carol's papers,
你不应该出售开萝尔的论文,
you shouldn't have made a date with an eighteen year old girl,
你也不应该和18岁的女孩子约会,你应该告诉爸妈所有的事情!
you should have told Mom and Dad everything!
本∶你说这些什么意思?
Ben: Why are you saying all that?
迈克∶只想作为证据.
Mike: Just to get it on the record.
杰森∶如果你在里面,事情还好商量,快点给我出来!
Jason: If you're in there, it'll go easier on you, if you come out now!
本∶迈克,我们该怎么办?
Ben: Mike, what are we gonna do?
迈克∶等一下你什么意思,"我们"?
Mike: Wait a minute, what do you mean, "we"?
杰森:迈克!
Jason: Mike!
本∶哈!他找的是你,不是我!
Ben: Hey, he's looking for you, not me!
迈克∶是我们!
Mike: OK, we!
本∶还有别的出口吗?
Ben: Is there any other way out of here?
迈克∶就这一个!
Mike: Just one!
玛莲∶你好,我要找……哦!哦!
Mylene: Hi, I'm looking for...oh oh!
本∶玛莲来了.那我可要出去了.
Ben: It's Mylene.So, then I came out.
(回到现在)
(present time)
迈克∶你终于还是听我的建议,给爸爸坦白了.
Mike: And I'm glad you finally took my advice about talking to Dad.
杰森∶好了,孩子们,这是很严肃的事情.本,你拿了一些不属于你的东西!并且你把它们卖给那些不应该得到的人!还有,你居然和一个18岁的女孩子约会!
Jason: Alright boys, this is serious.Ben, you took some things that didn't belong to you!You sold them to people who shouldn't have had them, and you made a date with an eighteen year old girl!
本∶事实上,是她约我的.
Ben: Actually, she made the date with me.
杰森∶我不管.你还逃课,
Jason: I don't care.
你没想过后果吗?
And you skipped classes at your own school, did you even think about that?
本∶恩,我真该编个借口……我是个白痴.
Ben: Well, actually I was gonna forge an excuse...I am an idiot.
杰森∶迈克,你呢,你不但不阻止他,还帮他去尝试,去做这些事情.
Jason: And Mike, you helped him try and pull this whole thing off.
迈克∶我坦白承认.
Mike: And I admitted it, like a man.
杰森∶那是因为你根本就没有别的选择.
Jason: Yeah, when you had no other way to go.
迈克∶的确是.
Mike: There is that, yes.
杰森∶嗨!你要知道,
Jason: Hey, Ben looks up to you as his example.
本一直是以你为榜样的.
You've got to share some of the responsibility of him,
你应该和我们一起,承担一些对他的责任.
with your mother and me.
本∶爸爸,你还记不记得,在我们很小的时候,你总是让我们自己选择处罚方式,因为我们选择的方式总是比你原本的处罚要重的多,对吗?
Ben: Dad, you remember when we were little kids, and you used to let us pick out our own punishment, 'cause we'd always give ourselves something worse than what you were gonna give us?
杰森∶是.
Jason: Yeah.
本∶那我们这次可不可以自己选择呢?
Ben: Are we gonna get to do that this time?
杰森:不行.
Jason: No.
本∶哦!看上去你好像问都不会问了!
Ben: Oh, like you weren't gonna ask too!
迈克∶嗨!爸爸,
Mike: Hey Dad, I am ready to share in that responsibility.
我已经准备好要和你们一起承担责任了.就让我来对他进行处罚吧.
Let me hand out the lad's punishment.
麦琪∶杜威尔先生,很感激你能把这件事情告诉我们.
Maggie: Mr.Dewitt, we do appreciate you bringing this to our attention.
校长∶没关系,这是我的工作……经常会让让人觉得很讨厌.
Principle: Hey, that's my job...as distasteful as it often is.
麦琪:我觉得学校应该没收本卖的钱.
Maggie: And it's only fair that the school get all the money Ben made.
杰森∶286美元!
Jason: Two hundred and eighty six dollars!
开萝尔∶这就是他的全部所得!这就是我整个高中的价值!
Carol: That's all he got!That's all my high school years are worth!
校长∶开萝尔,你要知道,你去的是公立学校.
Principle: Carol, wise up, you went to Public school.
杰森∶杜威饵先生,虽然本和迈克都不在麦维尔·杜威高中上学了,
Jason: Mr.Dewitt, even though Ben and Mike don't attend Dewey High,
但是,我保证我会重重的惩罚他们的.
I assure you they will be punished severely.
校长∶我会很感激的.
Principle: I appreciate that.
现在我已经管不着迈克了,
And while Mike is certainly out of my reach,
谢天谢地,
I just thank God that I had to work out that Extradition agreement with
我只要和本的中学签订引渡协议就好了.
Ben's Junior High school.
麦琪∶两位先生请你们稍等,
Maggie: So, if you two gentlemen will excuse us,
我和你爸爸要去讨论一些主要的惩罚方法.
your father and I have some major...major punishments to discuss.
对了,迈克,
Oh, and Mike, sometimes the one who set the example pays a higher price
做坏榜样的人所得到的惩罚要比学的人更重.
than the one who followed it.
本∶哦!妈妈,
Ben: Oh, and Mom, whatever punishment you should decide on,
你会采取什么惩罚.幸好没有被18岁的女孩子迷住!
thanks for not freaking out about the eighteen year old girl.
麦琪∶什么18岁的女孩?
Maggie: What eighteen year old girl?
杰森∶我正准备跟你说这件事的……这不是男女交易,我也没有为小家伙居然能让一个18岁的女孩子主动约他的本事而自豪.
Jason: Well, you know, I was gonna tell you about her...and this wasn't one of those male deals where I'm proud of the little horn ball for getting an eighteen year old to ask him out.
麦琪∶哦!不是吗?
Maggie: Oh, it wasn't!
杰森∶不,麦琪,
Jason: No, but I was under the gun Maggie;
我可是在枪口下,我只顾得上去讨论重要的事情了.
I only had time to discuss the important things.
麦琪∶哦!难道你觉得,
Maggie: Oh, so you think our thirteen year old son,
我们13岁的儿子差点就和18岁的女孩子约会了,这不要紧吗?
almost going out with an eighteen year old girl isn't important??
杰森∶噢不不不,这当然重要了,但是,
Jason: Oh no no no no that's...th...
和其他的事比较起来,还不是最重要的……你会惊异于他的天赋的.
that's important, but it's less important...it's under important from the ....
00:22:03,800
I think that err...Hey, you gotta admire the little guy's instincts.